## **Rory Devane**

Phone: (+44) 778 9256331

Address: Flat 4, 65 Kensington Gardens Square, London, W24DG

Email: rory.devane@gmail.com

Website: http://www.aircastle-solutions.com

Git: https://github.com/ashdown

## Summary

Full stack Web Developer specialising in responsive web design. Experienced in a multitude of technologies including JavaScript, CSS, PHP, Ruby and Heroku.

Experience of software development processes including Agile, Kanban, pair programming, Test Driven Development, and Behavior Driven Development. Briefly worked as a Scrum manager.

## **Employment History**

Jamie Oliver, London UK Senior Developer – Freelance January 2016 – Present

- Development lead for Jamie's Food Revolution 2016
- Development lead for Super Food Family Classics
- · Front end development using CSS (SCSS), JavaScript (jQuery) and PHP

Sky Broadcasting, London, UK Senior Developer - Freelance May 2013 to July 2015

- Leading front end development for ten major public facing websites.
- Forming tailored solutions for demanding and unusual requirements.
- Taking websites from concept, to development, and all the way to production via cloud platform deployment.
- Innovative Agile development team with Pair Programming.
- Contributing to open source projects (<u>Sky Web Toolkit</u>)
- International collaboration with developers based in England, Scotland, Spain, Israel and India.
- Front end web development using CSS (SCSS), and JavaScript (AngularJS, jQuery, Raphael)
- Back end web development using Ruby (Sinatra)
- BDD using Cucumber, TDD using Jasmine and QUnit

Betfair, London, UK Web Developer May 2012 to May 2013

- Front end development lead for 3 major public facing websites.
- Web development using CSS (LESS) and JavaScript (XUI, YUI, ¡Query).
- Scrum manager in an agile working environment.

BBC, London, UK Web Developer December 2009 to April 2012

- Development lead of <u>mobile Torch Relay site</u>, a key component of the BBCs London Olympic games coverage.
- Interim team lead for <u>mobile BBC Sport 2012 site</u>, an innovative semantic web solution.
- Led transition of <u>BBC Recipe Binder</u> site to responsive solution
- Led front end development of BBC Food site.
- Web development using CSS and JavaScript (jQuery, XUI, Zeptos) and PHP (Zend Framework)

Vertus Technologies, London, UK Web Developer - Freelance March 2009 to Devember 2009

Web development using CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Adobe Flash

Irish Heritage, Limerick City, Ireland Multimedia Developer – Freelance September 2008 to October 2008

Interactive display development and design using Adobe Flash

Sinead's Boutique, Limerick City, Ireland Web Developer – Freelance October 2008 to February 2009

Web Development using CSS and JavaScript

Firecrest Clinical, Limerick City, Ireland Multimedia Developer February 2007 to June 2008

Software development using Adobe Flash

Saffron Interactive, London, UK Multimedia Developer - Freelance September 2006 to December 2006

Multimedia development using Adobe Flash

## **Education**

1.1 Bsc (Hons) in Computing in Multimedia Systems, Dublin, Ireland, 20051.1 Bsc (Hons) in Information Technology and Telecommunications, Limerick, Ireland, 2004